A Guide to the Department of Conservation and Development, Division of History, Records, 1927-1950
Library of Virginia
- Series I. Correspondence, 1927-1950 (Accession 24806a)
  - Subseries A: Correspondence, 1927-1950
    - Additional Correspondence
      - White, Judge B.D. (Box 53, Folder 9)
      - Wolfe, J.B., Grottoes, VA (Box 53, Folder 10)
      - Wright, Mrs. W.W. (Box 54, Folder 1)
      - Wright, William A. (part one) (Box 54, Folder 2)
      - Wright, William A. (part two) (Box 54, Folder 3)
    - Topics
      - Wakefield Restoration (George Washington clippings) - See Also Oversize Box 1, Folder 6 (Box 54, Folder 4)
      - Water Planning (Natural Resources Committee) (Box 54, Folder 5)
      - William and Mary College (Box 54, Folder 6)
      - Williamsburg Restoration (Box 54, Folder 7)
      - Wright Brothers (Mr. W.C. Hall's file) - See Also Oversize Box 1, Folder 7 (Box 54, Folder 8)
      - Hall, Wilbur (Orville Wright Correspondence re: Weadon Home in Loudoun County) (Box 54, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence
      - Yale University Press - Yost, Paul M. (Box 54, Folder 10)
      - Yourell, R.M. - Yust, Walter (Box 54, Folder 11)
    - Topics
      - York Electro-Cast Company (Highway Markers) (Box 55, Folder 1)
      - Yorktown Sesquicentennial Handbook (Box 55, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence
      - Zehmer, George B. - Zorn, Jay (Box 55, Folder 3)
  - Subseries B: Correspndence, Dead File, 1927-1950
    This subseries is housed in 16 boxes and one oversize box and is arranged alphabetically by correspondent and subject. This subseries consists of incoming and outgoing correspondence from Division of History staff members. Topics include the historical marker program, historical marker inscriptions, installation, and maintenance, published guide to historical markers, Richmond Battlefield Park, and reports of History Division activities.
    The most significant correspondence are between William E. Carson, chairman of the Virginia Conservation Commission from 1926 to 1934, and Dr. Hamilton J. Eckenrode. These letters provide insight into the development, administration and problems of the historical marker program. Other topics include the Richmond Battlefield Park. Topics of a personal nature include Carson's fall in 1933 and death in 1942 and Eckenrode's bachelorhood.
    Notable correspondence concerning the historical marker program include letter to Carson from Eckenrode asking him to sooth Conrad's hurt feelings over mistakes Carson made in marker inscriptions (29 November 1927); letter to Carson from Eckenrode describing delays in the installation of Lynchburg markers (11 March 1930); correspondence regarding marker orders and delivery problems (23 October 1933, 25 October 1933, 16 February 1934, 24 March 1934, 18 August 1934, and 20 August 1934); correspondence describing problems with marker maintenance (17 February 1933, 10 March 1933, 11 April 1933, 27 September 1933 and 7 October 1933).
    Of note within the collection are correspondence describing the development of the Richmond Battlefield Park, especially between 1931 and 1934. Significant correspondence for 1931 include (5 January, 8 July, 9 July, 10 July, 17 July, 21 July, 30 July, 14 August, 18 August, 19 August, 20 August, 4 September, 8 September, 8 December, 11 December, 17 December and 18 December); for 1932 (29 March, 15 April, 21 April, 26 April, 28 April, 2 May, 18 May, 10 August, 12 October, 13 October, 19 November, 21 November, and 14 December); for 1933 (22 May, 7 June, 14 July, 20 July, 24 July, 27 July, 4 August, 23 August, 8 September, 11 September, 15 September, 20 September, 11 October, 23 November, and 25 November); and for 1934 (10-13 January, 17 January, 7 February, 14 February, 15 February, 19 February, 12 March, 15-17 March, 10 April, 14 May, 16 May and 14 July).
    Topics of a personal nature in the correspondence include Carson's fall, injury to his arm, and recovery in 1933 (12 August, 13 August, 16 August, 15 September, 18 October, 20 October, 23 October, 24 October, and 27 October) and Carson's poor health shortly before he died in 1942. Throughout their correspondence, Carson teased Eckenrode about being a bachelor and encouraged him to find a wife (10 September 1929, 6 November 1929, 7 November 1929, 27 September 1930, 22 December 1930, and 10 June 1941).
    The correspondence of Bryan Conrad, contain both business and personal letters, though most relate to his employment with the Division of History. Almost all of the office correspondence are between Conrad and Eckenrode. Topics include Conrad's employment status (27 June 1927, 28 March 1929) and field work installing markers including weekly reports (1927-1928). Personal letters between Conrad and his sister, Carter Bryan Conrad of Washington, D.C., are also included within Conrad's office correspondence. Topics include Conrad's divorce (19 October 1932), family and politics (8 May 1933, 19 September 1933, 9 January 1934, 6 December 1934). Also included are Conrad's personal correspondence, including a letter to Carter Bryan Conrad regarding the Edith Maxwell case and Franklin D. Roosevelt (17 November 1937), and correspondence with his daughter, Georgia Conrad (15 March 1935, 20 September 1935 and 18 May 1936 newspaper clipping).
    Correspondence between Douglas Southall Freeman and Eckenrode include Freeman's comments on marker inscriptions. Additional correspondence discuss the Richmond Battlefield Park (20 June 1933, 21 June 1933, 7 July 1933, 10 July 1933, 21 August 1933, 18 September 1933, 22 September 1933, 23 September 1933, 25 September 1933, 23 November 1933, 15 January 1934, 25 January 1934 and 5 February 1934).
    Wilbur C. Hall was chairman of the Conservation Commission from 1935 to 1939. Topics included in correspondence between Hall and Eckenrode are the Richmond Battlefield Park (23 February 1935, 6 April 1935 and 11 June 1935) and the WPA Historical Inventory Project (28 May 1936, 20 August 1937 and 4 December 1937).
    The correspondence of M.F. Pleasants, Field Assistant for the Division of History, describe the installation and maintenance of the historical markers. Additional information can be found under the headings Highway Department and Markers.
    Also of note is a typed 17 page transcript of the diary of Dr. John Waller Reins describing his ocean voyage from Norfolk, Virginia, to California, between 2 April 1849 and May 1849, filed with the correspondence of Mrs. Harris E. Willlingham and reports of the Division's work during World War II ( Virginia World War II History ).
    Additional correspondents include E. Griffith Dodson, Elmer O. Flippin, Dr. H.R. McIlwaine, N. Clarence Smith, Branch Spalding, and Dr. E.G. Swem.
    - Allyn, Rex M. (Box 55, Folder 4)
    - American Automobile Association, Washington, DC (J.A. Brown, Business Manager) - See Also Oversize Box 1, Folder 8 (Box 55, Folder 5)
    - Burson, R.E. (Box 55, Folder 6)
    - C.W.A. Project (1934) - Architectural Work (Box 55, Folder 7)
    - Carson, W.E. (1927) (Box 55, Folder 8)
    - Carson, W.E. (1928) (Box 55, Folder 9)
    - Carson, W.E. (1929) (Box 55, Folder 10)
    - Carson, W.E. (1930) (Box 56, Folder 1)
    - Carson, W.E. (1931) (Box 56, Folder 2)
    - Carson, W.E. (1932) (Box 56, Folder 3)
    - Carson, W.E. (1933) (Box 56, Folder 4)
    - Carson, W.E. (1934) (Box 56, Folder 5)
    - Carson, W.E. (1935-1942, 1946 & 1948) (Box 57, Folder 1)
    - Conrad, Col. Bryan (Office Correspondence, 1927) (Box 57, Folder 2)
    - Conrad, Col. Bryan (Office Correspondence, 1928) (Box 57, Folder 3)
    - Conrad, Col. Bryan (Office Correspondence, 1929) (Box 57, Folder 4)
    - Conrad, Col. Bryan (Office Correspondence, 1930-1937) (Box 57, Folder 5)
    - Conrad, Col. Bryan (Personal File, 1929-1932) (Box 57, Folder 6)
    - Conrad, Col. Bryan (Personal File, 1933-1934) (Box 58, Folder 1)
    - Conrad, Col. Bryan (Personal File, 1935-1938) (Box 58, Folder 2)
    - Conrad, Col. Bryan (Personal File, 1939-1942, 1946) (Box 58, Folder 3)
    - Colonial National Monument, Cramton Bill (General Correspondence) (Box 58, Folder 4)
    - Couch, W.T., Director, University of North Carolina Press, 1933-1943 (Box 58, Folder 5)
    - Culler, Mrs. Julia Abbott (Box 58, Folder 6)
    - Dietz, Mrs. Winifred (Box 58, Folder 7)
    - Directory of Federal and State Departments and Agencies in Virginia, 1940 (Box 58, Folder 8)
    - Dodson, E. Griffith (Correspondence File, 1927-1931) (Box 59, Folder 1)
    - Dodson, E. Griffith (Correspondence File, 1932-1933) (Box 59, Folder 2)
    - Eckenrode, Dr. Hamilton J. (Correspondence Sent to Col. Bryan Conrad, 1927-1930) (Box 59, Folder 3)
    - Eckenrode, Dr. Hamilton J. (Memorandums, 1928-1937) (Box 59, Folder 4)
    - Eckenrode, Dr. Hamilton J. (Personal Correspondence, 1928-1938) (Box 59, Folder 5)
    - Flippin, Elmer O. (1927-1930) - See Also Correspondence filed under Markers (Box 59, Folder 6)
    - Freeman, Dr. Douglas S. (1927-1932) (Box 60, Folder 1)
    - Freeman, Dr. Douglas S. (1933-1935) (Box 60, Folder 2)
    - Garden Week in Virginia Pamphlets, 1929, 1933-1941, 1947-1949 - See Also Oversize Box 1, Folder 9 (Box 60, Folder 3)
    - Gilliam, R.A. - See Correspondence filed under Markers
    - Goodwin, Dr. W.A.R. (Yorktown Sesquicentennial) (Box 60, Folder 4)
    - Gray, Rev. Arthur, West Point, VA (Box 60, Folder 5)
    - Hall, Wilbur C. (1928-1934) (Box 60, Folder 6)
    - Hall, Wilbur C. (1935) - part one (Box 60, Folder 7)
    - Hall, Wilbur C. (1935) - part two (Box 60, Folder 8)
    - Hall, Wilbur C. (1936) - part one (Box 61, Folder 1)
    - Hall, Wilbur C. (1936) - part two (Box 61, Folder 2)
    - Hall, Wilbur C. (1937) - part one (Box 61, Folder 3)
    - Hall, Wilbur C. (1937) - part two (Box 61, Folder 4)
    - Hall, Wilbur C. (1938) (Box 61, Folder 5)
    - Hall, Wilbur C. (1939-1944) (Box 61, Folder 6)
    - Harrison, Fairfax (Box 62, Folder 1)
    - Highway Department
      - District Engineer, Bristol, Virginia (Box 62, Folder 2)
      - District Engineer, Culpeper, Virginia (Box 62, Folder 3)
      - District Engineer, Fredericksburg, Virginia (Box 62, Folder 4)
      - District Engineer, Lynchburg, Virginia (Box 62, Folder 5)
      - District Engineer, Richmond, Virginia (Box 62, Folder 6)
      - District Engineer, Salem, Virginia (Box 62, Folder 7)
      - District Engineer, Staunton, Virginia (Box 62, Folder 8)
      - District Engineer, Suffolk, Virginia (Box 62, Folder 9)
      - Forrer, J.J., Assistant Engineer, Maintenance, Richmond, Virginia (Box 62, Folder 10)
      - Lambert, C.W., Assistant Engineer, Equipment, Richmond, Virginia (Box 62, Folder 11)
      - Mullen, C.S., Chief Engineer, Richmond, Virginia (Box 62, Folder 12)
      - Leech, Jr., Charles B., Equipment Engineer, Richmond, Virginia (Box 62, Folder 13)
      - Sawtelle, C.C., Equipment Engineer, Richmond, Virginia (Box 62, Folder 14)
      - Jr. Landscape Superintendent, Bristol District (Box 63, Folder 1)
      - Jr. Landscape Superintendent, Culpeper District (Box 63, Folder 2)
      - Jr. Landscape Superintendent, Fredericksburg District (Box 63, Folder 3)
      - Jr. Landscape Superintendent, Lynchburg District (Box 63, Folder 4)
      - Jr. Landscape Superintendent, Richmond District (Box 63, Folder 5)
      - Jr. Landscape Superintendent, Salem District (Box 63, Folder 6)
      - Jr. Landscape Superintendent, Staunton District (Box 63, Folder 7)
      - Jr. Landscape Superintendent, Suffolk District (Box 63, Folder 8)
      - Miscellaneous (Box 63, Folder 9)
      - Resident Engineers, Bristol District (Box 63, Folder 10)
      - Resident Engineers, Culpeper District (Box 63, Folder 11)
      - Resident Engineers, Fredericksburg District (Box 63, Folder 12)
      - Resident Engineers, Lynchburg District (Box 63, Folder 13)
      - Resident Engineers, Richmond District (Box 64, Folder 1)
      - Resident Engineers, Salem District (Box 64, Folder 2)
      - Resident Engineers, Staunton District (Box 64, Folder 3)
      - Resident Engineers, Suffolk District (Box 64, Folder 4)
    - Horseley, J.R., 1927-1942 (Box 64, Folder 5)
    - Horseley, Jr., 1928 (alphabetical) (Box 64, Folder 6)
    - Institutional Letters - Agreements Received (Box 64, Folder 7)
    - Institutional Letters - Agreements Not Received (Box 64, Folder 8)
    - Institutional Letters - Order Placed with Factory (Box 64, Folder 9)
    - Kegley, F.B., 1927-1934 (Box 64, Folder 10)
    - Kegley, F.B., 1935-1947 (Box 65, Folder 1)
    - Markers
      - Correspondence of E.O. Flippin Relating to Markers, 1928-1929 (9-4-2) (Box 65, Folder 2)
      - Correspondence of E.O. Flippin Relating to Historical Markers, 1930 (9-4-1) (Box 65, Folder 3)
      - Marker Booklet, Shenandoah Publishing House, 1929-1930 (9-6-2) (Box 65, Folder 4)
      - Correspondence of E.O. Flippin and R.A. Gilliam, 1930 (9-1) (Box 65, Folder 5)
      - Important Papers (R.A. Gilliam File), 1931 (2-9) (Box 65, Folder 6)
      - Dr. Eckenrode, Miscellaneous (R.A. Gilliam File), 1931 (9-1 to 9-5) (Box 65, Folder 7)
      - Richmond Battlefield Park (R.A. Gilliam File), 1931-1932 (7-7) (Box 65, Folder 8)
      - Correspondence of R.A. Gilliam, 1932 (9-1 to 9-5) (Box 65, Folder 9)
    - Marker Maintenance (Assistant Painters) (Box 65, Folder 10)
    - Martin, Col. Lawrence, Washington, DC (Box 66, Folder 1)
    - McIlwaine, Dr. H.R. (Box 66, Folder 2)
    - Millard, C.I. (Box 66, Folder 3)
    - Mullen, C.S. (Dept. of Highways) (Box 66, Folder 4)
    - Neale, H.J. (Landscape Engineer), 1937-1940 (Box 66, Folder 5)
    - Neale, H.J. (Landscape Engineer), 1941-1945 (Box 66, Folder 6)
    - Neale, H.J. (Landscape Engineer), 1946-1948 (Box 66, Folder 7)
    - Newspaper Clippings and Miscellaneous Printed Matter (Box 66, Folder 8)
    - Pleasants, M.F., 1927-1930 (Box 66, Folder 9)
    - Pleasants, M.F., 1931 (Box 67, Folder 1)
    - Pleasants, M.F., 1932-1933 (Box 67, Folder 2)
    - Pleasants, M.F., 1934-1937 (Box 67, Folder 3)
    - Pleasants, M.F., 1938-1944 (Box 67, Folder 4)
    - Pleasants, M.F., Marker Field Work, 1946-1948 (Box 67, Folder 5)
    - Salem Foundry and Machine Works, Inc., 1945-1946 (Box 67, Folder 6)
    - Salem Foundry and Machine Works, Inc., 1947-1948 (Box 67, Folder 7)
    - Sams, C. Whittle, Norfolk, VA (Box 68, Folder 1)
    - Schaadt, Mrs. C.W. (Box 68, Folder 2)
    - Shirley, Henry G. (Chairman Highway Commission), 1927-1941 (Box 68, Folder 3)
    - Shrines in Virginia, 1932-1933 (Box 68, Folder 4)
    - Skinnell, J.F. (Manager, WMBG Studio) (Box 68, Folder 5)
    - Smith, N. Clarence (Chairman), 1939-1940 (Box 68, Folder 6)
    - Smith, N. Clarence (Chairman), 1941-1942 (Box 68, Folder 7)
    - Spalding, Branch (National Park Service), 1933-1936 - See Also Oversize Box 1, Folder 10 (Box 68, Folder 8)
    - Sully, Julia (Box 69, Folder 1)
    - Swem, Dr. E.G., 1927-1930 (Box 69, Folder 2)
    - Swem, Dr. E.G., 1931-1936 (Box 69, Folder 3)
    - Traveling Expenses (Revolving Fund), Correspondence, A-L (Hotel Letters) (Box 69, Folder 4)
    - Traveling Expenses (Revolving Fund), Correspondence, M-Z (Hotel Letters) (Box 69, Folder 5)
    - Traveling Expenses, Bank Statements of Account, 1 July 1946 to 1 June 1948 (Box 69, Folder 6)
    - Virginia World War II History - See Also Oversize Box 1, Folder 11 (Box 69, Folder 7)
    - Virginia Writers' Project (Prefaces of Books and Pamphlets) (Box 70, Folder 1)
    - White, J. Stuart (Box 70, Folder 2)
    - Whitelock, Frances, Editor "East Texas", Longview, Texas (Box 70, Folder 3)
    - Wiles, Edmond R., Little Rock, Arkansas (Box 70, Folder 4)
    - Willingham, Mrs. Harris E. (Diary of Dr. John Waller Reins, and notes on old homes) (Box 70, Folder 5)
    - WMBG Broadcasting Studio, Richmond, VA (Box 70, Folder 6)
    - WPA Artists Project (Box 70, Folder 7)
    - (WPA) Federal Writers' Project, Dr. H.J. Eckenrode, Director for Virginia (Box 70, Folder 8)
    - (WPA Project) Historic Buildings, Sites, Etc. (Box 70, Folder 9)
    - Wright, Jr., Marcellus E., Project Engineer, Local Virginia Emergency Relief Administration (Box 70, Folder 10)
    - Yorktown Pageant, 1932 (Box 70, Folder 11)
    - Yorktown Investigation (Box 70, Folder 12)
    - Yorktown Sesquicentennial History (Campaign and Siege of Yorktown) (Box 70, Folder 13)
- Series II. Virginia War History Project, 1942-1946 (Accession 24806b)
  The Virginia War History Project series is housed in 10 boxes with oversized material separated and is arranged into two subseries. Subseries have been designated for Counties and Cities. The series consists of booklets, correspondence, lists, newspaper clippings, newsletters, pamphlets, photographs, programs, reports, and rosters.
  In September 1942 the Virginia Conservation Commission's Division of History and Archaeology, under the direction of Dr. Hamilton J. Eckenrode, began a war records collection program. Unable to continue the Division of History's historical marker program because of wartime rationing, Eckenrode sought to "record the history of the Old Dominion's war effort while the history is still fresh in the making, rather than wait until after the war when the events and details would be more obscured." The Conservation Commission began a correspondence program in which a non-salaried correspondent from each locality sent reports about local war activities and local effects and reaction to the war. The local correspondents also assisted the Virginia World War II History Commission with its' questionnaire, "Personal War Service Record of Virginia's Ward Dead" completed by the next of kin of Virginia's deceased servicemen.
  Most of the information in this series contains correspondence reports on local wartime conditions in Virginia from local correspondents mainly during 1943 with a few from 1944 and 1945. Topics include local opinion and reaction to war events and news, rosters of local service men and women, activities of local organizations, economic conditions and religious conditions. Unfortunately, the quantity and quality of these reports varied widely. Many only submitted a few reports. However, other localities submitted a substantial number of records. In addition, there are correspondence between the History Division and local correspondents related to the administration of the "Personal War Service Record of Virginia's War Dead" questionnaire on behalf of the Virginia World War II History Commission. These records were transferred to the Virginia World War II History Commission and are part of Record Group 68, accession 24805. A few localities submitted casualty lists.
  - Subseries A: Counties
    This subseries is housed in 9 boxes and one oversize box and is arranged alphabetically by county. This subseries consists of incoming correspondence and reports from local correspondents and replies from Division of History staff members. A few also include newspaper clippings about local soldiers and events. The bulk of the reports cover portions of 1943 and some 1944. The quality and frequency of the reports varied widely. Notable county reports include Arlington County (clippings from Washington, D.C. newspapers), Bedford County (reports on D-Day, 6-8 June 1944), Buchanan County, Buckingham County (1942-1943 issues of Seabees Buzz), Dinwiddie County (reaction to the war by Camp Lee service men, ca. 1944), Essex County (critical attitude), Fluvanna County, Halifax County, Henry County, Isle of Wight County, Loudoun County, Nelson County, Patrick County, Prince William County, Stafford County (including "Story of Stafford Evacuation" by Elizabeth Russell Powers, describing removal of 650 families for enlargement of Marine Base at Quantico in 1942), and Surry County.
    A few localities (Alleghany County, Franklin County, Giles County, Prince George County, Sussex County and Wise County) also gathered biographical information about soldiers often listing the soldiers name, age, physical description, name of parents, residence, education, marital status, and a brief military record. A few records include newspaper clippings and photographs.
    - Accomack County, 1943-1946 (Box 71, Folder 1)
    - Albemarle County, 1943-1946 (Box 71, Folder 2)
    - Alleghany County, 1943-1945 (Box 71, Folder 3)
    - Amelia County, 1942-1945 (Box 71, Folder 4)
    - Amherst County, 1943, 1945 (Box 71, Folder 5)
    - Appomattox County, 1942-1946 (Box 71, Folder 6)
    - Arlington County, 1943-1946 and newspaper clippings (Box 71, Folder 7)
    - Augusta County, 1942-1946 (Box 71, Folder 8)
    - Bath County, 1943-1946 (Box 71, Folder 9)
    - Bedford County, 1943-1946 (Box 71, Folder 10)
    - Bland County, 1943-1945 (Box 71, Folder 11)
    - Botetourt County, 1943, 1945 (Box 71, Folder 12)
    - Brunswick County, 1943-1946 (Box 71, Folder 13)
    - Buchanan County, 1942-1943, 1945-1946 (Box 71, Folder 14)
    - Buckingham County, 1942 (Box 72, Folder 1)
    - Buckingham County, 1943 (Box 72, Folder 2)
    - Buckingham County, 1944 (Box 72, Folder 3)
    - Bucking County, 1945-1946 (Box 72, Folder 4)
    - Campbell County, 1943-1946 (Box 72, Folder 5)
    - Caroline County, 1942-1943, 1945-1946 (Box 72, Folder 6)
    - Carroll County, 1943, 1945 (Box 72, Folder 7)
    - Charles City County, 1942-1945 (Box 72, Folder 8)
    - Charlotte County, 1942-1943, 1945 (Box 72, Folder 9)
    - Chesterfield County, 1943 (Box 72, Folder 10)
    - Clarke County, 1942-1943, 1945-1946 (Box 72, Folder 11)
    - Craig County, 1943-1946 (Box 72, Folder 12)
    - Culpeper County, 1942-1943, 1945-1946 (Box 72, Folder 13)
    - Cumberland County, 1942-1945 (Box 72, Folder 14)
    - Dickenson County, 1942-1943, 1945 (Box 73, Folder 1)
    - Dinwiddie County, 1943-1945 (Box 73, Folder 2)
    - Elizabeth City County - empty folder
    - Essex County, 1943-1946 (Box 73, Folder 3)
    - Fairfax County, 1943-1946 (Box 73, Folder 4)
    - Fauquier County, 1942-1943, 1945 (Also includes City of Warrenton) (Box 73, Folder 5)
    - Floyd County, 1943-1946 (Box 73, Folder 6)
    - Fluvanna County, 1943-1946 (Box 73, Folder 7)
    - Franklin County, 1942-1946 (Box 73, Folder 8)
    - Franklin County, Register Record of Soldiers of World War II (Box 73, Folder 9)
    - Frederick County, 1942-1943 (Box 73, Folder 10)
    - Giles County, 1942-1943 (Box 74, Folder 1)
    - Giles County, 1943 (Box 74, Folder 2)
    - Giles County, 1943-1946 (Box 74, Folder 3)
    - Gloucester County, 1942-1946 (Box 74, Folder 4)
    - Goochland County, 1942-1943, 1945 (Box 74, Folder 5)
    - Grayson County, 1943, 1945 (Box 74, Folder 6)
    - Greene County, 1943, 1945 (Box 74, Folder 7)
    - Greensville County, 1943-1945 (Box 74, Folder 8)
    - Halifax County, 1942-1945 (Box 74, Folder 9)
    - Hanover County, 1943-1945 (Box 74, Folder 10)
    - Henrico County, 1943 (Box 75, Folder 1)
    - Henry County, 1942-1943 (Box 75, Folder 2)
    - Henry County, 1943 (Box 75, Folder 3)
    - Henry County, 1943-1944 (Box 75, Folder 4)
    - Henry County, 1944-1945 (See Also Oversize Box 2, Folder 1) (Box 75, Folder 5)
    - Highland County, 1943, 1945 (Box 75, Folder 6)
    - Isle of Wight County, 1943-1946 (Box 75, Folder 7)
    - James City County, 1942-1943, 1945 (Box 75, Folder 8)
    - King and Queen County, 1942-1946 (Box 75, Folder 9)
    - King George County, 1942-1943, 1945 (Box 76, Folder 1)
    - King William County, 1942-1946 (Box 76, Folder 2)
    - Lancaster County, 1942-1945 (Box 76, Folder 3)
    - Lee County, 1943-1945 (Box 76, Folder 4)
    - Loudoun County, 1942-1945 (Also includes Leesburg) (Box 76, Folder 5)
    - Louisa County, 1942-1946 (Box 76, Folder 6)
    - Lunenburg County, 1942-1946 (Box 76, Folder 7)
    - Madison County, 1942-1946 (Box 76, Folder 8)
    - Mathews County, 1942-1946 (Box 76, Folder 9)
    - Mecklenburg County, 1943-1945 (Box 76, Folder 10)
    - Middlesex County, 1942-1945 (Box 76, Folder 11)